

ÁLVARO ENRIQUE RUANO

alvaro.ruano90@outlook.com https://alvaroruano.me

PROFILE

Software Engineer helping businesses to accomplish their goals through the use of technology, always oriented to provide the right solution for the specific need.

Ten years of experience working on software development projects on roles of: Software developer, Business Analyst, Project Manager and Software Engineering Manager.

SKILLS

- Team management (up to 14 people)
- FrontEnd development: AngularJS, ASP.Net MVC & WebForms, Django
- BackEnd development: WebAPI, WCF, MS SQL, MySQL, Sybase ASE, MongoDB
- DevOps: Git, TFS VS, Docker, CircleCI, TravisCI, CodeCov
- AWS Cloud: EC2, RDS, S3, Lambda, Cloud Formation

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING MANAGER • CONDUENT • FEB 2017 - PRESENT

In charge of development for the "Workers Compensation Bill Review" platform, from the inception of the process on the data capture applications, to the end reporting compliance information to the distinct state governments in the USA; this is achieved through the correct management of technologies and the development team, as well as good understanding of the business requirements.

BUSINESS ANALYST • CONDUENT • APR 2015 - FEB 2017

In charge of the correct performance of the platforms used to report compliance information to the distinct state governments in the USA, through the correct administration of technological and human resources, as well as the interpretation of the business requirements.

SR. DEVELOPER • AGROMERCANTIL BANK • APR 2015 - FEB 2017

In charge of the software development projects through all the phases of the lifecycle, from requirements analysis to deployment. Also provide production support for the systems created. Subsequently, in a role of team leader, take control of a portion of the project portfolio.

JR. DEVELOPER • CITIBANK • APR 2015 - FEB 2017

Design and develop the new functions for the Electronic Banking systems used in Central America. Execute the tasks established in the Software Development Lifecycle, completing the deliverables required.

EDUCATION

MBA • ENAE BUSINESS SCHOOL • 2020 (EXPECTED)

MASTER OF FINANCE • RAFAEL LANDÍVAR UNIVERSITY • 2016

• Academic Excellence Diploma

INFORMATION SYSTEMS ENGINEERING • RAFAEL LANDÍVAR UNIVERSITY • 2013

- Magna Cum Laude
- Excellence in Values Award 2012 Engineering Students Association (AEI)
- Basic Sciences Olimpics 2009 (third place in Math) San Carlos University